Flesh to touch...Flesh to burn! Don't keep the Wicker Man waiting!
The Wicker Man is a horror film directed by Robin Hardy.
Police sergeant Neil Howie is called to an island village in search of
a missing girl whom the locals claim never existed.
The investigation is further complicated as Howie’s religious
views clash with those of the island’s residents.
Sergeant Neil Howie, played by Edward Woodward.
Lord Summerisle, played by Christopher Lee.
Willow MacGreagor, played by Britt Ekland.
Miss Rose, played by Diane Cilento.
Librarian, played by Ingrid Pitt.
Broome, played by Roy Boyd.
The Wicker Man is a 1973 British folk horror film directed by Robin Hardy and starring
Edward Woodward, Britt Ekland, Diane Cilento, Ingrid Pitt and Christopher Lee.
The screenplay is by Anthony Shaffer, inspired by David Pinner's 1967
novel Ritual, and Paul Giovanni composed the film score.
The plot centres on the visit of a police officer, Sergeant Neil Howie, to the
fictional, isolated Scottish island of Summerisle in search of a missing girl.
Howie, a devout Christian, is appalled to find that the inhabitants of the island
have abandoned Christianity and now practise a form of Celtic paganism.
The Wicker Man is well regarded by critics.
Film magazine Cinefantastique described it as "The Citizen Kane of horror movies", and in 2004,
Total Film magazine named The Wicker Man the sixth-greatest British film of all time.
It also won the 1978 Saturn Award for Best Horror Film.
The final scene was number 45 on Bravo's 100 Scariest Movie Moments, and during the 2012 Summer Olympics
opening ceremony, it was included as part of a sequence that celebrated British cinema.
The film brought the wicker man into modern popular culture.
In 1989, Shaffer wrote a script treatment for The Loathsome
Lambton Worm, a direct sequel with fantasy elements.
Hardy had no interest in the project, and it went unproduced.
In 2006, a poorly received American remake starring Nicolas Cage was released, from which
Hardy and others involved with the original have dissociated themselves.
In 2011, a spiritual sequel written and directed by Hardy, The Wicker
Tree, was released; it featured Lee in a cameo appearance.
In 2013, the original U.S.
theatrical version of The Wicker Man was digitally restored and released.
The film explores themes of virgin, island, based on
novel or book, sacrifice, scotland.
The tone is dark.